callie gorman

calliegorman.design linkedin.com/in/calliegorman

calliegorman4@gmail.com 201-638-4568

DESIGN SKILLS

User Research

Competitive Analysis

Usability Testing

Persona Creation

Sitemaps

User Stories/Flows

Sketching

Wireframing

Prototyping

Branding

Visual Design

FRONTEND

HTML

CSS

Bootstrap

Javascript

jQuery

Github

TOOLS

Sketch

Figma

Invision

myBalsamiq

Draw.io

Illustrator

InDesign

callie gorman. Digital Marketer turned Designer

I am a UX Designer with 5+ years of experience marketing in the tech industry.

My education in psychology and work as a digital strategist have taught me how to conduct effective user research, allowing me to create intuitive and user-centered designs that can increase user engagement rates to meet business goals.

RECENT PROJECTS

Led the UX process, including design creation, competitive and user research, and usability testing for:

vicarious

view prototype | view case study

A mobile travel app that prompts users to provides brief updates on each day of travel for family and friends.

connected

view prototype | view case study

A cloud-based storage application that features an intuitive interface, collaboration options, and dashboard personalization.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Digital Strategist

Jan 2015 - Dec 2017

IBM Analytics, NYC | Remote

- Increased conversion rates by 2% on Analytics web pages by implementing A/B tests and making design changes
- Worked in an Agile environment to improve the user experience of ibm.com live chat by testing wait times, questions, and design features
- Led strategy for 10+ quarterly digital campaigns that contributed more than \$1M of yearly marketing created revenue

Digital Lead

Dec 2016 - May 2017

Tribeca Film Festival, NYC | Remote

Developed digital and social media strategy for IBM / Tribeca Film Festival partnership, driving 100+ customers to private sales events

Project Manager

Jan 2015 - April 2016

IBM Outthink Tour, NYC | Remote

Selected as lead project manager on a premiere event series, managing 10 teammates for events that drove 2000 net new clients

LEADERSHIP

IBM Marketing Mentor

Jan 2015 - May 2017

Chosen by managers to mentor five new employees during their onboarding

EDUCATION

UX/UI Design Program, Bloc

Dec 2017 - July 2018

Intensive user-centered design program building web and mobile app designs

College of the Holy Cross

May 2012

BA, Psychology, Pre-Business